Samant Sahu

2301-4C,New Mahada Building Sarvakar Nagar,Powai

Mobile No.: 09167381391

Email: n.samantasahu@gmail.com

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Full Name: Samant Sahu

Gender: Male

Date of Birth: May 27, 1991

Marital Status: Single Occupation: Graduate

Interests: Reading, swimming, football, traveling

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Experienced Technical Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the Healthcare, Retail, Payment industry. Skilled in ERP/CRM/POS System Implementation, Servers, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Software Deployment, and SFA Implementation. Aiming to utilize my strong prioritization skills and analytical ability to achieve the goals of your company.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelor Of Technology In Computer Science & Engineering Institute Of Advanced Computer & Research Rayagada,Odisha

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr.Implementation Consultant SUNPHARMA INDUSTRIES LTD

Payroll Company:Proteus Technologies Pvt Ltd May-2017- July-2019

- Business & Functional understanding and requirement gathering
- End to End CRM, ERP & POS Implementation & presales support.
- Responsible for implementing part or all of the technical solution to the client, in accordance with an agreed technical design.
- Assist clients with all stages of a product implementation with POCs, Gap analysis and data mapping, Installation and configuration, owning development of custom functionalities, UAT and End User Training.
- Provides planning and design support for the development of solution architectures that will be implemented in a multiple system environment.

- Responsible for customer satisfaction with project implementations and ongoing maintenance of the relationship at the appropriate levels. Identify gaps and recommendations for performance improvement on behalf of the client.
- Responsible for multiple project implementations, removing roadblocks, directing client questions to the appropriate parties and coordinating internal priorities.
- Participate as needed to support the Client Executive in onsite customer implementation workshops to understand the customer's workflow, objectives, and needs, taking a consultative approach recommending way to integrate Enterprise solutions into their infrastructure to meet their needs.
- Handle client calls to bring the issues/requests to a closure via screen sharing / Emails as per the quality parameters set.
- Keeping the clients updated with the progress on the concerns raised.
- Providing post product/project go live support for resolving issues.
- Giving demos of Products through WebEx/Skype or face to face meetings.
- Often leads small to medium technical projects.
- Make Use Cases and studying system capabilities, writing specifications.
- Document all test plans and implement various test cases to resolve all defects in test processes and monitor all system change requests and develop implementation guides.
- Responsible for the documentation(BRD,FRD,OQ,PQ,IQ).
- Understanding of data formats (XML, JSON).
- Responsible for the deployment in Multiple Server.
- Experience in using a CRM solution such as Sales Force Automation.
- Experience in managing software as a service (SAAS) implementations.
- Write SQL queries to generate reports.

Implementation Consultant HINDUSTAN PETROLIUM CORPORATION LIMITED

Payroll Company:SRIT India Pvt Ltd April-2016- May-2017 Bangalore,Karnataka

- Requirement gathering, functional analysis, business rule, test cases writing, UAT. Analyse and design business processes.
- Review project deliverables for completeness and quality and compliance with established project standards, process capability development.
- Develop product requirement based on input gathered from variety of sources including analysis results and the feedback from the user community Team project/ Support management.

- Prepare and develop test strategies and test plans.
- JD Edwards Support. Give support to E-procurement site.
- Perform technical presentations, Coordinate proof of Concepts, solutions and product demonstration.
- Work closely with sales team and Partners by participating and supporting all sales strategies and business goals
- Provide accurate and useful project or issue status reports.
- Provides planning and design support for the development of solution architectures that will be implemented in a multiple system environment.
- Providing day-to-day technical and functional assistance to E-Procurement users.
- Monitor, manage and communicate with developers on defects.
- Wrote complex SQL statements providing back-end solutions to production issues, monitoring, and reporting.

TECHNICAL ANALYST TECKRAFT INFOSOLUTION PVT LTD

March 2015 - April 2016 Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Implementation, Administration, Managing the entire ERP project operations as a Super User for production, inspection, purchase, stores, sales and accounts departments.
- Provides courteous, efficient, and professional technical support by phone and email to customers across a broad range of industries.
- Troubleshoots intermediate to advanced problems and recommends appropriate actions.
- Provides support case follow-up until resolution, ensuring proper escalation procedures are followed for unresolved issues.
- Manages customer expectations and competing priorities.
- Escalates issues and works directly with Research and Development to resolve complex support problems.
- Effectively co-ordinate with all the departments to map the organizations business process.
- Production Management: Adept at handling day-to-day changes in production activities & responsible for maintaining the Process routes.
- Training and guiding the end users in engineering, purchase, inventory, production, planning, sales and account modules of the ERP System.

 User creation, authorization control and system support for customization/development of sessions in ERPs, documenting user requirements and developing specifications for customization.

SYSTEM ENGINEER SIDDHI SALES PVT LTD

Sept 2014 - March 2015

Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Served as a System Engineer, Manage and monitor all install system and infrastructure
- Responsible for installation, configuration and maintenance services.
- Install, configure, test and maintain operating system application software and system management tools.
- Installing and operating Windows desktop and server operating systems.
- Configure and install various networks devices and services(i.e. routers ,switches, firewall)
- Review computer systems and resolve problems.
- Address all desktop issues on priority basis.
- Troubleshoot and debug software and hardware problems.
- Install and Configure MS Outlook and troubleshoot the same.

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

Geo fencing with Voice Assistant (06/2017 - 12/2018)

Successfully implemented geofencing by using AI in SFA

Auto Mode for SFA (01/2018 - 05/2018)

The application works without network.

CLM Dashboard/E-Detailing For SFA (08/2018 - Present)

User can play the multimedia file and track the details and share within the group.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux.

Programming Languages: C,C++,PL/SQL,SQL **Databases:** Oracle 10g,SQL Server 2000/2005/2008

Web Technologies: MySQL,Wildfly 10.0/Jboss

Messaging: Lotus Notes, MS Outlook

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Strong motivational skills
- Ability to produce best result in pressure situation.
- Ability to work in team as well as in group.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Won best cadet award in NCC.
- Got many prizes in sports like football.
- Participated in robotics workshop in GIACR Tech Fest.

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent Hindi: Fluent Odiya: Native